The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
After being pushed this far,
I have been enlightened.
Thank you for helping me realize
that even a heartless person
cannot escape the Life and Death reincarnation cycle !
The reincarnation cycle
is the Dao of Life and Death.
How is this possible !?
The Dao of reincarnation
should be ruthless.
Unfortunately
ruthlessness
and heartlessness
are separated by only a thin line.
But that's what made the difference.
Domain battles
between cultivators
are just them proving their own Dao to each other.
And this battle
was won by Ceng Niu.
Ancestor is right
but Red Butterfly is also impressive
as she achieved enlightenment from this loss.
If I could have reached Soul Transformation
even the reincarnation cycle
would be suppressed by ruthlessness.
However
I haven't lost yet !
Four Spirits Killing Formation !
Today
is the day I complete the Heaven Defying Bead.
Metal spirit,
explode !
Ceng Niu,
even if I need to sacrifice my 4 spirits,
I will kill you !
My 3 spirits,
explode together !
Since my soul was injured
my cultivation has fallen to Early stage Soul Formation.
Red Butterfly's attack
will greatly injure me even if I survive.
Is mutual destruction
the outcome Zhuque Zi is looking for ?
I can only gamble once
to see if he will intervene.
If you kill me,
then we both die !
Let's see that !
Enough...
The outcome of this duel is clear.
Ceng Niu,
you won.
From now on,
you are a disciple of Suzaku,
under the Immortal's Path Sect.
I will grant you one wish.
What do you desire ?
Feel free to ask.
I want this.
You !
Then I’ll give you half of it.
Where there is mercy, there is forgiveness.
Thank you Suzaku.
This duel
has drained you both greatly.
Now
you both need to rest.
You can go.
What exactly does Zhuque Zi want ?
Forbidden area
Country of Suzaku
The competition to become the 15th generation Suzaku is imminent.
Tell me,
how are the preparations going ?
Ancestor,
disciple is diligently following your teachings.
I heard that
your furnace escaped.
Is this true ?
Ancestor,
Zi Xin must have been freed by someone.
They broke my restrictions
so their cultivation must surpass mine.
This matter isn’t simple,
I will find the culprit.
Don't bother,
you won't have to look for her.
Your master has found
a better furnace candidate for you.
The type of furnace I need is rare...
Who is Ancestor referring to ?
In the duel between Red Butterfly and Ceng Niu
both their domains
have evolved.
But their souls
have been severely injured.
If you can devour Red Butterfly’s spiritual energy and domain,
you will
completely absorb
her Ruthless Domain.
As a result,
your chance of reaching Ascendant
will increase.
Did the Ancestor take her in
just for me ?
Thank you Ancestor !
You
must not disappoint me now.
Yes !
It is a bit regrettable
that we must do this to Red Butterfly...
Your master is getting old.
I can't bear
to do certain things anymore.
Ancestor,
don't worry.
That way the title of Suzaku
won't be passed to an outsider.
It will be me or Junior Sister.
No one else.
Enough,
you can leave.
Understood.
Red Butterfly's cave
Country of Suzaku
Ceng Niu...
Next time,
I will kill you !
I’ll grant your wish for you.
Who is it !?
I'm Qian Feng,
we met earlier today...
What are you doing ?
I want your domain
and your four elemental spirits !
How ?
This…
Qing He,
if you cannot help her overcome her fate,
Red Butterfly will be dead
by the end of the war.
What she predicted
was this death...
Did Senior Brother succeed ?
From now on,
she is my cultivation furnace.
I named her Heartless.
Congratulations on your breakthrough, Senior Brother.
When will I
be like you, Senior Brother ?
Don't worry,
take your time.
Heartless is the third person whose domain I’ve devoured.
Junior Sister,
one day
you will become my furnace too.
I...
will become the next Suzaku !
It’s a pity that...
there can only be
one Suzaku.
Liu Mei...
Disciple is listening.
You cultivate the Thousand Illusions Ruthless Domain.
Now that only your last illusion is missing
you need to find a profound domain
and devour it.
By transforming it into your final illusion
the Thousand Illusions Ruthless Domain
will reach completion.
The original person I prepared for you
was Zhou Yi from the Five Elements Sect.
His Craze Domain was extremely rare.
Unfortunately,
this person completely disappeared
within the Celestial Realm.
Ancestor, don't worry.
Disciple will create more avatars
and descend the mountain
to comprehend the Dao.
You once had an avatar
in the country of Zhao, under the Xuan Dao Sect.
During a sect competition
you met a disciple from the Heng Yue Sect
named Wang Lin.
Do you remember him ?
Wang Lin...
Him ?!
That's right,
Ceng Niu
is Wang Lin.
He
is the person I found for you.
Red Butterfly’s Dao heart was shattered,
leaving no room for improvement.
But Wang Lin is different.
You must watch him closely
and when his domain is ripe,
you must refine him
into your cultivation furnace.
When that happens,
his Life and Death Domain
will be yours.
At that time,
compared to Feng’er
you will be even more likely
to inherit the title of Suzaku.
Disciple obeys.
Wang Lin...
He was the only one
who resisted my avatar’s charm constitution.
In just 500 years,
he’s caught the eye of the Ancestor.
This man isn't simple.
Perhaps I should take this chance
to leave a mark in his heart
for future use.
From now on,
Main hall
Country of Suzaku
you will enter seclusion with me.
Recently,
more and more tattoo puppets have infiltrated the surface.
The Forsaken Immortal Clan
must be plotting something.
We must conserve our strength
to prepare for the worst.
Understood.
Do you
remember Yunque Zi ?
Wasn't he the one
who competed with you for the title of 14th Suzaku ?
Correct,
after failing to seize the position,
he began wandering planet Suzaku.
I thought he had given up on fighting
but unexpectedly
he secretly trained his own disciples.
His goal
is pretty clear.
But the title of Suzaku
must never fall to Yunque Zi's faction.
Is that clear ?
Understood.
Junior Brother,
since you released Qian Feng's furnace, Zi Xin,
and took her under your wing...
That means you are declaring war...
I won't let you get away with this.
I won't spare a single one
of your 4 disciples.
Senior Brother,
we've fought throughout our entire lives.
Since that's the case,
then let's see
if it's your disciples
or my chosen candidates
that will prevail.
Wang Lin...
Although Zhuque Zi promised my safety,
Red Butterfly is still alive
and the Immortal's Path Sect is acting suspiciously.
They cannot be trusted.
My injuries are severe
so the priority now
is to return to Zhao
to find a secluded place to recover
and breakthrough to Late stage Soul Formation.
Transfer shift !
Ceng Niu,
even if I must self-destruct my Origin Soul,
I will send you to your death !
What kind of formation is this !?
Junior Sister Red Butterfly,
I promised to help you.
I kept
my word...
Far North
of the Suzaku continent
Junior Ceng Niu,
you’ve finally arrived.
A Soul Transformation old monster ?
Who are you ?
Li Yuanfeng, Suzerain of Xue Yue.
I'm here on behalf of Red Butterfly
to take your life.
I heard that Xue Yue
was forcefully raised to a rank 5 cultivation country.
7 Soul Formation Elders
went to Suzaku with Red Butterfly.
By using an unorthodox technique,
only one survived
and reached Soul Transformation.
I assume that’s you.
Thanks to the opportunity given by Red Butterfly,
I had a breakthrough.
But I cannot forget my roots...
You severed Red Butterfly’s arm.
And Red Butterfly
is the hope of Xue Yue.
For both personal and public reasons
I will not let you live another day.
If I face a Soul Transformation now,
I stand no chance.
Even with my soul injured,
I should still be able to open spatial rifts.
I have set a formation here.
Spatial rifts
cannot be opened.
Your Star Compass
is useless.
Oh... right,
I forgot to tell you.
The formation also prevents teleportation.
This formation
is called
the Heaven-Sealing Formation !
Ceng Niu,
this time
you have no escape.
Still refusing to give up ?
Sun Tai,
come quickly !
Another Soul Transformation ?
Junior Ceng Niu,
as I told you,
today
is the day you die.
To let go of the consequences of my actions
is to ignore the law of cause and effect
like scattered ink.
As destiny falls
in exchange for this moment of tainted dreams.
It makes the mountains lose their colors,
wither and melt into rivers.
Who can deceive
the law of the heavens ?
Countless generations
have tried before me.
But how could I not catch my dreams
within my warm fingers ?
You're at my side when I'm alone
giving me the strength to fight the will of the heavens.
Fortunately, my mind was open and honest.
I'm sorry we never got to see the fireworks
in the streets.
Can I break the vortex of our destiny ?
Can I break the rules ?
To run towards you !
I will fight the law of the heavens and the law of cause and effect
to cut down this tribulation with my own hands
and break through the reincarnation cycle.
All of that for the stars in your eyes.
I wish to bend this dream for the fire in my heart.
If your soul is willing to wander,
can I still take your hands
and hold them tight ?
I will defy the heavens and prevent the stars from falling.
I will overthrow the Immortals and the Demons in my heart.
I dream of destroying
the shackles of our fate.
You're the only one that can ignore the law of cause and effect.
You're the hardest to let go of.
I want to be with you again
so I can look in your eyes.
Even for a moment, it's worth it.